Guide to the Rice University Margarett Root Brown College Records, 1965-2014 UA 074
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Margarett Root Brown College Records
1965-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Margarett Root Brown College (Rice University)
UA 074
20.5 Linear Feet (35 boxes)
4.2 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_001 (4.2 MB)
9.7 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_002 (9.7 MB)
4.23 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_003 (4.23 MB)
0.02 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_004 (0.02 GB)
0.18 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_005 (0.18 GB)
4.33 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0074aip_006 (4.33 MB)
Correspondence, newsclippings, obituaries, minutes, freshman materials, publications, governmental and budget documents as well as other information relating to the general operation of Brown College. There are also files on the Brown students such as lists of members and room assignments. Brown College was dedicated on October 3, 1965 and was filled primarily by women who had volunteered to leave Jones College, then the only women's college, to start a new college.
Historical Sketch
In 1963 Jones was the only women's college at Rice, and there was such a severe housing shortage that some Rice women were being housed in another university's dorms. In October of that year, George R. Brown and his wife Alice Pratt Brown donated one million dollars through the Brown Foundation to build a new dorm for women at Rice. The new college was established in memory of their sister-in-law, Margarett Root Brown, (1896-1963) who was the wife of the also late Hermann Brown. Margarett Brown was devoted to the fine arts as an art critic and collector and served on the boards of several of organizations. As a tribute to her love of the arts, the first floor of Brown College houses a wide variety of paintings and antique furniture donated by the George R. Brown family and others.
The College was dedicated on October 3, 1965 and was filled primarily by women who had volunteered to leave Jones College to start a new college. Since then other colleges have been added to Rice, and beginning in 1971 some colleges went co-ed. Brown held out as the last all female college until 1987 when it agreed to accept male members.
The College is an eight-story masonry structure on the northeast campus. The high-rise was devised to spare trees. In 2001 new construction will change the Brown College complex. An addition will connect to Brown College on four levels and will extend west of the College in the area occupied by the current Jones Masters' House. New Brown Commons will anchor the west end of Brown Quadrangle with the existing Brown Master's House on the South Side.
Excerpted from Rice University Construction Web Page and Brown College Web Page
Scope and Contents
The Margarett Root Brown records consist of 20.5 linear feet. Files included here pertain to activities, correspondence, newsclippings, obituaries, minutes, freshman materials, publications, governmental and budget documents as well as other information relating to the general operation of the college. There are also files on the Brown students such as lists of members and room assignments. In addition, there are many scrapbooks and slides.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
No access restrictions, this material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The original records held by Woodson Research Center (.75 linear feet) were mostly from the files of one of the Brown College Associates, Nancy Parker Boothe. Other material included photocopies of newspaper articles, programs, etc., collected by the Woodson staff.
In November 2002 Woodson received twenty-two Eclipse File boxes of Brown College records dating from 1965-87 from Nancy Henry, Brown College Coordinator. In 2014, Nancy Henry donated scrapbooks. Also in that year, John Muller, President 2013/2014, started uploading documents to the Brown College Digital Archive.
Related Materials
See Rice University Archives for records of other Rice University residential colleges. Contact Woodson Research Center staff for assistance.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Universities and colleges; Social life and customs
Document Types
calendars; obituaries; minutes (administrative records); awards; photographs; legal documents; guidebooks; clippings (information artifacts)
Subjects (Persons)
Brown, Margarett Root
Subjects (Corporations)
Margarett Root Brown College (Rice University); Rice University--residential college system
- Series I: Alumni/Associates, 1965-1992; 174403
  - Associates, 1965-1966; 174406 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Associates, 1966-1967; 174407 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum, 1966-1967; 174408 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Associates, 1967-1968; 174409 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Associates, 1968-1969; 174410 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Associates, 1969-1970; 174411 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Associates, 1970-1971; 174412 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Associates, 1971-1972; 174413 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Associates, 1972-1973; 174414 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Associates, 1973-1974; 174415 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Associates, 1974-1975; 174416 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alumni, 1975-1976; 174417 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Associates, 1975-1976; 174418 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alumni, 1976-1977; 174419 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Associates, 1976-1977; 174420 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alumni, 1977-1978; 174421 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Associates, 1977-1978; 174422 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alumni, 1978-1979; 174423 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Associates, 1978-1979; 174424 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alumni, 1979-1980; 174425 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Associates, 1979-1980; 174426 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Associates, 1980-1981; 174427 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Associates, 1981-1982; 174428 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Associates, 1982-1983; 174429 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Associates, 1983-1984; 174430 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Associates, 1984-1985; 174431 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Associates, 1985-1986; 174432 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Associates, 1986-1987; 174433 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Associates, 1987-1993; 174434 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "The Associated Press", 1987-1989, 1992; 174435 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series II: College Courses, 1968-1987; 174404
  - 1968-1969, 174436 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1970-1971, 174437 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Career Counseling, 1971-1972; 174438 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1971-1972, 174439 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1972-1973, 174440 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1973-1974, 174441 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1974-1975, 174442 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1975-1976, 174443 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1976-1977, 174444 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1977-1978, 174445 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1978-1979, 174446 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1979-1980, 174447 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1983-1984, 174448 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1985-1986, 174449 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1986-1987, 174450 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series III: Freshman/O-Week, 1965-2018; 174405
  - Freshman Materials, 1965-1966; 174451 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Freshman Materials, 1966-1967; 174452 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Freshman Materials, 1967-1968; 174453 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Freshman Materials, 1968-1969; 174454 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Freshman Handbook Worksheets, 1969-1970; 174455 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Freshman Mailings and Orientation, 1969-1970; 174456 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Freshman Lists, 1970-1971; 174457 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Freshman Mailings, 1970-1971; 174458 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Freshman Week, 1970-1971; 35911 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Freshman Mailings, 1971-1972; 174459 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Freshman Packet, 1971-1972; 174460 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Freshman Week, 1971-1972; 174461 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Freshman Week, 1972-1973; 174462 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Materials and Mailings, 1973-1974; 35896 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Materials and Mailings, 1974-1975; 35878 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Materials, 1975-1976; 35858 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Materials, 1976-1977; 35838 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Materials, 1977-1978; 35823 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Materials, 1978-1979; 35808 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Freshman Materials and Mailings, 1979-1980; 35781 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Materials, 1980-1981; 35768 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Materials, 1981-1982; 35756 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Materials, 1982-1983; 35742 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Materials, 1983-1984; 35730 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Materials, 1984-1985; 35718 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Materials, 1985-1986; 35705 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Freshman Materials, 1986-1987; 35695 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Brown Gang! O-Week Book, 1991; 174463 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - O-Week Book and Materials, 1992; 174464 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - OO7-Week Book, 1995; 174465 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Wild Wild West O-Week Book, 2001; 35688 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - AlOha Week Book, 2002; 35687 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - MafiosO Week Book, 2003; 35686 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - IncognitO-Week book, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cameo-Week Book, 2007; 172963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - UFO-Week Book, 2008; 172979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Presto Week Book, 2009; 172976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - O-Week Materials, 2009-2010; 174466 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - KokomO-Week Book (2), 2010; 172972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - RingO-Week Book, 2011; 172977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jack SparrO-Week Book, 2012; 172970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Super MariO-Week book, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Governance, 1965-2012; 174467
  - Government, 1965-1966; 174468 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jobs, 1965-1966; 174469 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations, 1965-1966; 174470 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Government, 1966-1967; 174471 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1967-1968; 174472 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Court Report, 1967-1968; 174473 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Government, 1967-1968; 174474 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - (A Handbook of) Policies, Rules, and Regulations Affecting Undergraduate Life, 1968; 174475 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1968-1969; 174476 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Government, 1968-1969; 174477 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Budget, 1969-1970; 174478 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Court Abstract, 1969-1970; 174479 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Government, 1969-1970; 174480 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jobs, 1969-1970; 174481 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Budget, 1970-1971; 174482 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Government, 1970-1971; 174483 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Jobs, 1970-1971; 174484 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Budget, 1971-1972; 174485 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Government, 1971-1972; 174486 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Budget, 1972-1973; 35915 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Government, 1972-1973; 35910 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Budget, 1973-1974; 35899 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Government, 1973-1974; 35895 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1974-1975; 35883 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Government, 1974-1975; 35877 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Policies and Regulations Affecting Student Life, 1974-1975; 174487 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1975-1976; 35863 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Government, 1975-1976; 35857 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Budget, 1976-1977; 35844 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Government, 1976-1977; 35837 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1977-1978; 35827 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Government, 1977-1978; 35822 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Mailings, 1977-1978; 35821 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1978-1979; 35811 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Government, 1978-1979; 35807 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Mailings, 1978-1979; 35806 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1979-1980; 35796 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Government, 1979-1980; 35792 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Budget, 1980-1981; 35783 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Government, 1980-1981; 35780 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Mailings, 1980-1981; 35779 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1981-1982; 35770 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Government, 1981-1982; 35767 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Budget, 1982-1983; 35758 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Gift (for 15th Anniversary), 1982-1983; 35755 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Government, 1982-1983; 35754 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Budget, 1983-1984; 35745 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gifts, 1983-1984; 35741 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Government, 1983-1984; 35740 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Government, 1984-1985; 35729 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Court Report, 1985-1986; 35719 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Gifts, 1985-1986; 35717 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Government, 1985-1986; 35716 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Government, 1986-1987; 35704 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Government, 1987-1988; 35694 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Court, 1992-1994; 172965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Secretary Handbook, 2005-2008; 184724 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Government, 2011-2012; 159282 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Constitution, n.d.; 172964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series V: Housing, 1965-1987; 174488
  - Construction and Dedication, 1965; 174489 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Housing, 1965-1966; 174490 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Room Assignments, 1965-1966; 174491 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Housing, 1966-1967; 174492 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Room Assignments, 1966-1967; 174493 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Housing, 1967-1968; 174494 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Room Rates, 1970-1971; 174495 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Room Assignments, 1971-1972; 174496 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Safety and Security, 1971-1972; 174497 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Co-ed Housing, 1972-1973; 35914 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Room Assignments and RCMAC, 1972-1973; 35906 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Security, 1972-1973; 35905 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Mailouts, 1973-1974; 35894 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Room Assignments, 1973-1974; 35890 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Security, 1973-1974; 35889 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Co-ed Transfer Policy, 1974-1975; 35882 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Food Service, 1974-1975; 35879 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Residential Contracts, 1974-1975; 35873 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Room Assignments, 1974-1975; 35872 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Security, 1974-1975; 35871 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds, RCMAC, 1975-1976; 174498 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Co-ed College, 1975-1976; 35862 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Room Assignments, 1975-1976; 35854 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Security, 1975-1976; 35853 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Summer Shutdown, 1975-1976; 35851 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Co-ed Colleges, 1976-1977; 35843 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Flood, 1976-1977; 35840 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Food and Housing, 1976-1977; 35839 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Room Assignments, 1976-1977; 35834 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Co-ed Colleges, 1977-1978; 35826 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Room Assignments, 1977-1978; 35818 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Room Assignments, 1978-1979; 35803 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Room Assignments, 1979-1980; 35789 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Room Assignments, 1980-1981; 35776 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Room Assignments, 1981-1982; 35764 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Room Assignments, 1982-1983; 35751 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Room Assignments, 1983-1984; 35736 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Room Assignments, 1984-1985; 35726 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Room Assignments, 1985-1986; 35713 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Co-ed Conversion, 1986-1987; 35708 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Room Assignments, 1986-1987; 35701 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - College Coordinator Monthly Tasks, 1996; 174638 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Series VI: Members, 1965-1999; 174499
  - 1965-1966, 174500 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - 1966-1967, 174501 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - 1967-1968, 174502 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - 1968-1969, 174503 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - 1969-1970, 174504 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - 1970-1971, 174505 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - 1971-1972, 174506 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - 1972-1973, 174507 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - 1973-1974, 174508 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - 1974-1975, 174509 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1975-1976, 174510 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1976-1977, 174511 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1977-1978, 174512 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1978-1979, 174513 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1979-1980, 174514 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1980-1981, 174515 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1981-1982, 174516 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1982-1983, 174517 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1983-1984, 174518 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1984-1985, 174519 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1985-1986, 174520 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 1986-1987, 174521 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - 1987-1988, 174522 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - 1989-1990, 174523 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - 1993-1994, 174524 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 1995-1996, 174525 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - 1997-1998, 174526 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - 1998-1999, 174527 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Series VII: Minutes, 1965-1999; 174528
  - 1965-1966, 174529 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - 1966-1967, 174530 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - 1967-1968, 174531 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - 1968-1969, 174532 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - 1969-1970, 174533 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - 1970-1971, 174534 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Brown College Cabinet, 1971-1972; 174535 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Forum, 1971-1972; 174536 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Harem, 1971-1972; 174537 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1972-1973, 174538 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1974-1975, 174539 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1975-1976, 174540 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1976-1977, 174541 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1977-1978, 174542 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1978-1979, 174543 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1979-1980, 174544 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1980-1981, 174545 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1981-1982, 174546 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1982-1983, 174547 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1983-1984, 174548 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 1984-1985, 174549 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - 1985-1986, 174550 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - 1986-1987, 174551 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - 1987-1988, 174552 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - 1988-1989, 174553 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - 1989-1990, 174554 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - 1990-1991, 174555 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - 1991-1992, 174556 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - 1992-1993, 174557 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - 1993-1994, 174558 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - 1994-1995, 174559 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1995-1996, 174560 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1996-1997, 174561 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1997-1998, 174562 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1998-1999, 174563 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Publications, 1965-; 174564
  - ca. 1960s-1970s, 174565 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1965-1966, 174566 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1966-1967, 174567 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1967-1968, 174568 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1969-1970, 174569 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1970-1971, 174570 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1971-1972, 174571 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1972-1973, 174572 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1973-1974, 174573 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 1983-1984, 174574 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Newsclippings, 1993-; 174575 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Series IX: Student Life, 1965-2011; 174576
  - Activities, 1965-1966; 174577 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Awards and Honors, 1965-1966; 174578 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Activities, 1966-1967; 174579 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Awards and Honors, 1966-1967; 174580 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sports, 1966-1967; 174581 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Activities, 1967-1968; 174582 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Awards and Honors, 1967-1968; 174583 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Commencement, 1967-1968; 174584 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Activities, 1968-1969; 174585 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Awards and Honors, 1968-1969; 174586 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Commencement, 1968-1969; 174587 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Awards and Honors, 1969-1970; 174588 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Commencement, 1969-1970; 174589 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Sports, 1969-1970; 174590 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Awards and Honors, 1970-1971; 174591 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Commencement, 1970-1971; 174592 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Activities, 1971-1972; 174593 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Awards and Honors, 1971-1972; 174594 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Commencement, 1971-1972; 174595 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1972-1973; 35918 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Honors, 1972-1973; 35916 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Commencement, 1972-1973; 35912 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Sports, 1972-1973; 35904 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Activities, 1973-1974; 35902 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Awards and Honors, 1973-1974; 35900 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Commencement, 1973-1974; 35897 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Sports, 1973-1974; 35888 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Activities, 1974-1975; 35886 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Awards and Honors, 1974-1975; 35884 (Box 714, Folder 13)
  - Commencement, 1974-1975; 35880 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Sports, 1974-1975; 35870 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Activities, 1975-1976; 35868 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Awards and Honors, 1975-1976; 35865 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Commencement, 1975-1976; 35860 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sports, 1975-1976; 35852 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1976-1977; 35849 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Awards and Honors, 1976-1977; 35846 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Commencement, 1976-1977; 35841 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sports, 1976-1977; 35833 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Activities, 1977-1978; 35831 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Awards and Honors, 1977-1978; 35828 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Commencement, 1977-1978; 35824 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Sports, 1977-1978; 35817 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Activities, 1978-1979; 35815 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Awards and Honors, 1978-1979; 35812 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Commencement, 1978-1979; 35809 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sports, 1978-1979; 35802 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Activities, 1979-1980; 35800 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Awards and Honors, 1979-1980; 35797 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Commencement, 1979-1980; 35794 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Sports, 1979-1980; 35788 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Activities (15th Anniversary), 1980-1981; 35786 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Awards and Honors, 1980-1981; 35784 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Commencement, 1980-1981; 35782 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sports, 1980-1981; 35775 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Activities, 1981-1982; 35773 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Honors, 1981-1982; 35771 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Commencement, 1981-1982; 35769 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Sports, 1981-1982; 35763 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Activities, 1982-1983; 35761 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Awards and Honors, 1982-1983; 35759 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Commencement, 1982-1983; 35757 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sports, 1982-1983; 35750 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Activities, 1983-1984; 35748 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Awards and Honors, 1983-1984; 35746 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Commencement, 1983-1984; 35743 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Activities, 1984-1985; 35734 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Awards and Honors, 1984-1985; 35732 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Commencement, 1984-1985; 35731 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Activities, 1985-1986; 35724 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Awards and Honors, 1985-1986; 35722 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Commencement, 1985-1986; 35720 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Activities, 1986-1987; 35711 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Awards and Honors, 1986-1987; 35709 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Commencement, 1986-1987; 35706 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Activities, 1988-1989; 174599 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Activities, 1989-1990; 174600 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Activities, 1990-1991; 174601 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Activities, 1992-1993; 174602 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Activities, 1993-1994; 174603 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Activities, 1995-1996; 174604 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Activities, 1996-1997; 174605 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1997-1998; 174606 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Activities, 1999-2000; 174607 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Activities, 2000-2005; 174608 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Activities, 2007-2009; 174609 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Activities, 2010-2011; 174610 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Talent Show poster, February 3, 2011; 160482 (Map-drawer 147, Item 4)
    General Note
    Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs, Part 3 of 3 (UA 226-3)
  - Bacchanalia poster, April 8, 2011; 160483 (Map-drawer 147, Item 5)
  - Invitations, n.d.; 174611 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Series X: Photographs, 1965-2010; 174596
  - 15th Anniversary, October 12, 1980; 174612 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Beer Bike, 1972-1973, 1989, n.d.; 174613 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - College Secretary, 1971-1972, ca. 1980s; 174614 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Construction, Exterior and Interior, 1965-1966; 174615 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Masters and Associates, 1965-1966, 1980-1982, 1985; 174616 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Senior Punch Card IDs, 1972; 174617 (Box 17, Folder 15)